Lets start NLP with learning Regular Expressions

'artists,' 
1


'It may well be,' 
2


'An artist is identical with an anarchist,' 
3


'So it is,' 
4


'Nonsense!' 
5


'It is you who are unpoetical,' 
6


'Must you go?' 
7


'I tell you,' 
8


'And even then,' 
9


'There again,' 
10


'It is things going right,' 
11


'Really,' 
12


'I beg your pardon,' 
13


'You don't expect me,' 
14


'No, I don't,' 
15


'Don't you think, then,' 
16


'I beg your pardon ?' 
17


'Am I not serious about my anarchism ?' 
18


'My dear fellow!' 
19


'Mr. Syme,' 
20


'Do you ?' 
21


'What do you mean ?' 
22


'My dear Miss Gregory,' 
23


'Is he really an anarchist, then?' 
24


'Only in that sense I speak of,' 
25


'He wouldn't really use--bombs or that sort of thing?'


26


'Good Lord, no!' 
27


'I was waiting for you,' 
28


'Certainly. About what?' 
29


'All the same,' 
30

'But may I ask if you have been standing out here in the dark only
to resume our little argument?'


31


'Mr. Syme,' 
32


'Indeed!'


33


'I am very sorry,' 
34


'I am afraid my fury and your insult are too shocking to be wiped
out even with an apology,' 
35


'In what I said?'


36


'There are degrees of seriousness,' 
37


'And in no other sense,' 
38


'Serious!' 
39


'Very well,' 
40


'You spoke just now of having a religion. Is it really true that
you have one?'


41


'Then may I ask you to swear by whatever gods or saints your
religion involves that you will not reveal what I am now going to
tell you to any son of Adam, and especially not to the police?
Will you swear that! If you will take upon yourself this awful
abnegations if you will consent to burden your soul with a vow
that you should never make and a knowledge you should never dream
about, I will promise you in return--'


42


'I will promise you a very entertaining evening.' 
43


'Your offer,' 
44


'I think,' 
45


'Will you take a little supper?' 
46


'Oh, bring me some lobster mayonnaise.'


47


'What will you drink?' 
48


'Thank you!' 
49


'Excuse me if I enjoy myself rather obviously!' 
50


'You are not asleep, I assure you,' 
51


'And who are we?' 
52


'It is quite simple,' 
53


'Oh!' 
54


'Yes, we are serious about everything,' 
55


'If in a few moments this table begins to turn round a little,
don't put it down to your inroads into the champagne. I don't wish
you to do yourself an injustice.'


56


'Certainly!' 
57


'You must not mind it,' 
58


'Quite so,' 
59

'Mr. Joseph Chamberlain.' 
60


'I must ask you to forgive me all these formalities,' 
61

'we have to be very strict here.'


62


'And now, my dear Mr. Syme,' 
63


'It does seem to have a moral under all its gaiety,' 
64


'To abolish God!' 
65


'And Right and Left,' 
66


'You spoke of a second question,' 
67


'With pleasure,' 
68


'The answer is simple,' 
69


'The history of the thing might amuse you,' 
70


'What is his name?' 
71


'You would not know it,' 
72


'But whenever he gives advice it is always something as startling
as an epigram, and yet as practical as the Bank of England. I said
to him, 'What disguise will hide me from the world? What can I find
more respectable than bishops and majors?' 
73


'You took me in,' 
74


'What do you call this tremendous President of yours?'


75


'I feel somehow as if you were my mother, Syme,' 
76


'My dear fellow.' 
77


'As a matter of fact, everything is ready for me on this table,' 
78


'I have only to get the form of election finished,' 
79


'Why is it,' 
80


'Well, damn it all! this is the funniest situation I have ever been
in in my life, and I am going to act accordingly. Gregory, I gave
you a promise before I came into this place. That promise I would
keep under red-hot pincers. Would you give me, for my own safety, a
little promise of the same kind? '


81


'Yes,' 
82


'Your secret?' 
83


'Yes,' 
84


'You must have bewitched me, but I feel a furious curiosity about
you. Yes, I will swear not to tell the anarchists anything you tell
me. But look sharp, for they will be here in a couple of minutes.'


85


'Well,' 
86


'What do you say?' 
87


'Yes,' 
88
######################################################################
, 'it may
well be on such a night of clouds and cruel colours that there is
brought forth upon the earth such a portent as a respectable poet.
You say you are a poet of law; I say you are a contradiction in
terms. I only wonder there were not comets and earthquakes on the
night you appeared in this garden.'


89
, 'And
what is Victoria now that you have got there ?' 
90
, 'what is there poetical about
being in revolt ? You might as well say that it is poetical to be
sea-sick. Being sick is a revolt. Both being sick and being
rebellious may be the wholesome thing on certain desperate
occasions; but I'm hanged if I can see why they are poetical.
Revolt in the abstract is--revolting. It's mere vomiting.'


91
, 'that is poetical I Our
digestions, for instance, going sacredly and silently right, that
is the foundation of all poetry. Yes, the most poetical thing, more
poetical than the flowers, more poetical than the stars--the most
poetical thing in the world is not being sick.'


92
, 'the examples you choose--'


93
, 'I forgot we had abolished
all conventions.'


94
, 'to revolutionise society on this
lawn ?'


95
; 'but I suppose that if you were serious
about your anarchism, that is exactly what you would do.'


96
, 'that I am
serious about my anarchism?'


97
, 'do the people who talk like you and my
brother often mean what they say ? Do you mean what you say now ?'


98
; 'or if you prefer
it, in that nonsense.'


99
, 'that has to be done anonymously.'


100
; 'about order and anarchy.
There is your precious order, that lean, iron lamp, ugly and
barren; and there is anarchy, rich, living, reproducing
itself--there is anarchy, splendid in green and gold.'


101
, 'just at present you only
see the tree by the light of the lamp. I wonder when you would ever
see the lamp by the light of the tree.' 
102
, 'I
did not stand here to resume our argument, but to end it for ever.'


103
, 'this evening you succeeded in doing something
rather remarkable. You did something to me that no man born of
woman has ever succeeded in doing before.'


104
, 'you think me serious? You think
me a flaneur who lets fall occasional truths. You do not think that
in a deeper, a more deadly sense, I am serious.'


105
, 'you shall see
something more serious than either drink or religion.'


106
, 'we are all Catholics now.'


107
, 'is far too idiotic to be declined. You say
that a poet is always an anarchist. I disagree; but I hope at least
that he is always a sportsman. Permit me, here and now, to swear as
a Christian, and promise as a good comrade and a fellow-artist,
that I will not report anything of this, whatever it is, to the
police. And now, in the name of Colney Hatch, what is it?'


108
, 'that we will
call a cab.'


109
; 'but I trust I can behave like a gentleman in either
condition. May I smoke?'


110
; 'it's a kind of screw.'


111
, 'a kind of screw. How simple that
is!'


112
, 'now we are
quite cosy, so let us talk properly. Now no human words can give
you any notion of why I brought you here. It was one of those quite
arbitrary emotions, like jumping off a cliff or falling in love.
Suffice it to say that you were an inexpressibly irritating fellow,
and, to do you justice, you are still. I would break twenty oaths
of secrecy for the pleasure of taking you down a peg. That way you
have of lighting a cigar would make a priest break the seal of
confession. Well, you said that you were quite certain I was not a
serious anarchist. Does this place strike you as being serious?'


113
; 'but may I ask you two questions? You need not fear to give
me information, because, as you remember, you very wisely extorted
from me a promise not to tell the police, a promise I shall
certainly keep. So it is in mere curiosity that I make my queries.
First of all, what is it really all about? What is it you object
to? You want to abolish Government?'


114
, 'I hope
you will abolish them too. They are much more troublesome to me.'


115
, 'Down! down!
presumptuous human reason!' 
116
, 'Let the weak perish; it is
the Law.' 
117
, 'What disguise will hide me from the world? What can I find
more respectable than bishops and majors?' 
118
, 'I congratulate you. A great
career!'


119
, 'and the ceremony will probably be the shortest possible.'


120
, 'then I snatch up this cloak and stick,
stuff these other things into my pocket, step out of a door in
this cavern, which opens on the river, where there is a steam-tug
already waiting for me, and then--then--oh, the wild joy of being
Thursday!' 
121
, 'that I think you are quite a decent
fellow? Why do I positively like you, Gregory?' 
122
, 'Is it because you
are such an ass?'


123
, 'a promise. I swore before God
that I would not tell your secret to the police. Will you swear by
Humanity, or whatever beastly thing you believe in, that you will
not tell my secret to the anarchists?'


124
, 'I have a secret.' 
125
, 'Will you
swear?'


126
, 'I don't know how to tell you the truth
more shortly than by saying that your expedient of dressing up as
an aimless poet is not confined to you or your President. We have
known the dodge for some time at Scotland Yard.'


127
, 'I am a police detective. But I think I
hear your friends coming.'


128
$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$$
. 'You might
transpose the words anywhere. An anarchist is an artist. The man
who throws a bomb is an artist, because he prefers a great moment
to everything. He sees how much more valuable is one burst of
blazing light, one peal of perfect thunder, than the mere common
bodies of a few shapeless policemen. An artist disregards all
governments, abolishes all conventions. The poet delights in
disorder only. If it were not so, the most poetical thing in the
world would be the Underground Railway.'


129
. 'Why do all the clerks and navvies in the
railway trains look so sad and tired, so very sad and tired? I will
tell you. It is because they know that the train is going right. It
is because they know that whatever place they have taken a ticket
for that place they will reach. It is because after they have
passed Sloane Square they know that the next station must be
Victoria, and nothing but Victoria. Oh, their wild rapture! oh,
their eyes like stars and their souls again in Eden, if the next
station were unaccountably Baker Street!'


130
. 'If what you
say of clerks is true, they can only be as prosaic as your poetry.
The rare, strange thing is to hit the mark; the gross, obvious
thing is to miss it. We feel it is epical when man with one wild
arrow strikes a distant bird. Is it not also epical when man with
one wild engine strikes a distant station? Chaos is dull; because
in chaos the train might indeed go anywhere, to Baker Street or to
Bagdad. But man is a magician, and his whole magic is in this, that
he does say Victoria, and lo! it is Victoria. No, take your books
of mere poetry and prose; let me read a time table, with tears of
pride. Take your Byron, who commemorates the defeats of man; give
me Bradshaw, who commemorates his victories. Give me Bradshaw, I
say!'


131
. 'Might I have a moment's
conversation?'


132
. 'About this and this,' 
133
. 'No duel
could wipe it out. If I struck you dead I could not wipe it out.
There is only one way by which that insult can be erased, and that
way I choose. I am going, at the possible sacrifice of my life and
honour, to prove to you that you were wrong in what you said.'


134
. 'I have never
doubted that you were perfectly sincere in this sense, that you
thought what you said well worth saying, that you thought a
paradox might wake men up to a neglected truth.'


135
. 'Good Lord! is this street serious? Are these
damned Chinese lanterns serious? Is the whole caboodle serious?
One comes here and talks a pack of bosh, and perhaps some sense as
well, but I should think very little of a man who didn't keep
something in the background of his life that was more serious than
all this talking--something more serious, whether it was religion
or only drink.'


136
. 'The pate
de foie gras is not good here, but I can recommend the game.'


137
. 'I shall only have a crepe de menthe myself; I have
dined. But the champagne can really be trusted. Do let me start you
with a half-bottle of Pommery at least?'


138
. 'You are very good.'


139
. 'I don't often have the luck to have a dream like this. It
is new to me for a nightmare to lead to a lobster. It is commonly
the other way.'


140
. 'You are, on the
contrary, close to the most actual and rousing moment of your
existence. Ah, here comes your champagne! I admit that there may be
a slight disproportion, let us say, between the inner arrangements
of this excellent hotel and its simple and unpretentious exterior.
But that is all our modesty. We are the most modest men that ever
lived on earth.'


141
. 'We are the serious
anarchists, in whom you do not believe.'


142
. 'You do yourselves well in drinks.'


143
. 'Try one of
mine.'


144
. 'I know your passion for law and
order,' 
145
. 'We
do not only want to upset a few despotisms and police regulations;
that sort of anarchism does exist, but it is a mere branch of the
Nonconformists. We dig deeper and we blow you higher. We wish to
deny all those arbitrary distinctions of vice and virtue, honour
and treachery, upon which mere rebels base themselves. The silly
sentimentalists of the French Revolution talked of the Rights of
Man! We hate Rights as we hate Wrongs. We have abolished Right and
Wrong.'


146
. 'In all your present acts and
surroundings there is a scientific attempt at secrecy. I have an
aunt who lived over a shop, but this is the first time I have
found people living from preference under a public-house. You have
a heavy iron door. You cannot pass it without submitting to the
humiliation of calling yourself Mr. Chamberlain. You surround
yourself with steel instruments which make the place, if I may say
so, more impressive than homelike. May I ask why, after taking all
this trouble to barricade yourselves in the bowels of the earth,
you then parade your whole secret by talking about anarchism to
every silly woman in Saffron Park?'


147
. 'I told you I was a serious
anarchist, and you did not believe me. Nor do they believe me.
Unless I took them into this infernal room they would not believe
me.'


148
. 'That is his greatness.
Caesar and Napoleon put all their genius into being heard of, and
they were heard of. He puts all his genius into not being heard of,
and he is not heard of. But you cannot be for five minutes in the
room with him without feeling that Caesar and Napoleon would have
been children in his hands.'


149
. 'You want a safe disguise, do you?
You want a dress which will guarantee you harmless; a dress in
which no one would ever look for a bomb?' 
150
. 'Why, then, dress up as an anarchist, you
fool!' 
151
. 'Nobody will ever expect
you to do anything dangerous then.' 
152
. 'It is really a smart dodge.'


153
. 'I feel that I can confide anything to you, as you have
promised to tell nobody. In fact, I will confide to you something
that I would not say in so many words to the anarchists who will be
coming to the room in about ten minutes. We shall, of course, go
through a form of election; but I don't mind telling you that it is
practically certain what the result will be.' 
154
. 'It is almost a settled thing that I am to be
Thursday.'


155
. 'Have you got a secret?'


156
